Guide to the Edwin Robert Anderson Seligman papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries I.1: Cataloged
    - Taft, William H.
    - Tannenbaum, Frank
    - Taussig, Frank William
    - Tawney, R.H
    - Taylor, Horace
    - Tebb, Sidney
    - Thatcher, Thomas D
    - Thayer, William Roscoe
    - Thomas Garrigue
    - Thomas, John Lloyd
    - Thomas, M. Carey
    - Thomas, Norman
    - Thorndike, Ashley Horace
    - Thorp, Willard Long
    - Tillard, Oswald G
    - Tooke, Thomas
    - Treadway, Charles Tenr
    - Trent, William P
    - Tugwell, Rexf Guy
    - Turgot, Anne R.U.
    - Tuttle, Charles A
    - Tweed, Harrison
    - Tyler, Harry Walter
    - Van Doren, Carl
    - Van Doren, Mark
    - Vanderlip, Frank Arthur
    - Viner, Jacob
    - Vinogradoff, P
    - Wagner, Adolph
    - Wagner, Robert Ferdinand
    - Walcott, Charles Doolittle
    - Wald, Lillian D
    - Walker, Francis
    - Wallace, Henry A.
    - Wallas, Graham
    - Walras, Leon
    - Walters, Edgar
    - Ward, Lester F
    - Ward, William H.
    - Ware, William Robert
    - Warner, A.G.
    - Warren, George Frederick
    - Warren, Howard Crosby
    - Washington, Mrs. Booker T.
    - Watson, Thomas J
    - Waymouth, Bernard
    - Weatherly, Ulysses Grant
    - Webb, Beatrice (Mrs. Sidney)
    - Weber, Max
    - Weizmann, Chaim
    - Weld, William Ernest
    - Welling, Richard
    - Welliver, Judson Churchill
    - Wells, David Ames
    - Wells, Herbert George
    - West, Max
    - Westergaard, Harold
    - Weston, Stephen F
    - Whitaker, Albert C
    - White, Andrew Dickinson
    - White, E.D.
    - White, Horace
    - Whitney, Arthur
    - Whitney, Edward B
    - Wicksell, Knut
    - Wieser, Friedrich von
    - Wigmore, John H
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman
    - Willeox, Walter F
    - Williams, George Huntington
    - Williams, Talcott
    - Willoughby, W.F.
    - Willis, H.P.
    - Wilson, James
    - Wilson, Thomas Woodrow
    - Winder, William H
    - Winn, Henry
    - Wise, Otto I
    - Wise, Stephen S.
    - Wood, Edith Elmer
    - Woodbridge, Frederick James Eugene
    - Woodward, George
    - Woodward, Robert Simpson
    - Wright, Carroll D
    - Young, Allyn Abbott
    - Young, Benjamin Loring
    - Young, James Carleton
    - Young, John Parke
    - Young, Swen D
    - Young, W.F.
  - Subseries I.2: Uncataloged Correspondence
    - Uncataloged correspondence, 1875-1883 (Box 1, Folder 15 - 16)
    - Uncataloged correspondence, 1886-1897 (Box 2, Folder 17 - 22)
    - Uncataloged correspondence, 1898-1904 (Box 3, Folder 23 - 24)
    - Uncataloged correspondence, 1905-1912 (Box 4, Folder 25 - 29)
    - Uncataloged correspondence, 1913-1914 (Box 5, Folder 30 - 31)
    - Uncataloged correspondence, 1915-1916 (Box 5A, Folder 30 - 31)
  - Subseries I.3: Correspondence (received)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 32 - 33)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1919-1920 (Box 7, Folder 34 - 35)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1920-1921 (Box 8, Folder 36 - 38)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1922a & 1922b (Box 9, Folder 39 - 40)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1922c & 1923a (Box 10, Folder 41 - 42)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1923b & 1924a (Box 11, Folder 43 - 44)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1924b & 1925a (Box 12, Folder 45 - 46)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1925b & 1926a (Box 13, Folder 47 - 48)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1926b & 1927a (Box 14, Folder 49 - 50)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1927b & 1928a (Box 15, Folder 51 - 52)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1928b & 1929a (Box 16, Folder 53 - 54)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1929b & 1930a (Box 17, Folder 55 - 56)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1930b, 1931a & 1931b (Box 18, Folder 57 - 59)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1932a & 1932b (Box 19, Folder 60 - 61)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1933a, 1933b & 1934 (Box 20, Folder 62 - 64)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1935 & 1936 (Box 21, Folder 65 - 66)
    - Uncataloged correspondence received, 1937 & 1938 (Box 22, Folder 67 - 68)
  - Subseries I.4: Correspondence(sent)
    - Uncataloged correspondence sent, 1919 - 1924 (Box 23, Folder 69 - 70)
    - Uncataloged correspondence sent, 1925 - 1931 (Box 24, Folder 71 - 72)
    - Uncataloged correspondence sent, 1932 - 1934 (Box 25, Folder 73 - 74)
    - Uncataloged correspondence sent, 1934 - 1938 (Box 26, Folder 75 - 76)
- Series II: Arranged Files
  - Academic freedom (Box 27)
  - A.A.U.P., 1921 & 1922 (Box 28)
  - A.A.U.P., 1924-1930 (Box 28)
  - A.A.U.P., 1929 & 1930 (Box 28)
  - A.E.A. Finance Committee (Box 29)
  - A.E.A. Nominating Committee (Box 29)
  - A.E.A. War Finance (Box 29)
  - Authors' Club (Box 30)
  - Automobile Installment Selling (Box 31)
  - Barnard Correspondence (Box 31 & 32)
  - Census, 1919-1922 (Box 32)
  - Checks (Box 33 & 34)
  - Christmas Cards (Box 34 & 35)
  - Clark, John Bates (Box 35)
  - Coal, Iron Co. (Box 35)
  - Code Authority of the Millinery Industry (Box 36)
  - Columbia, 1911-1930 (Box 36 & 37)
  - Columbia-Cattell Case (Box 37)
  - Cuba Received (Box 37)
  - Cuba Sent (Box 38)
  - Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 38)
  - Eurpoe, 1912 & 1913 (Box 39)
  - Farm Relief (Sent), 1928 (Box 39)
  - Farm Relief (Box 40)
  - Installment Selling (Box 41 - 43)
  - Instruction (Committee on) (Box 43)
  - Lake Placid (Box 44)
  - League of Nations (Box 44)
  - Lomansy (Box 44)
  - Public Health Instruction (Box 45)
  - Real Estate (Box 46 & 47)
  - Resale Price Maintenance (Box 47)
  - Rosanoff (Box 48)
  - Ross Case (Box 48)
  - San Salvador (Box 48)
  - Shore Owners Association of Lake Placid (Box 49 - 52)
  - State Tax Commission (Box 52)
  - Sugar Institute Case (Box 53)
  - Taxation (Committee on) (Box 53)
  - University in Exile (Box 54)
  - Father, School, and College - I-III (Box 57 & 58)
  - Papers: School, College, University (Box 58)
  - College Notebooks (Box 59)
  - Law School Notebooks (Box 60)
  - Personal (Box 60)
  - Bills Paid (Box 61)
  - Correspondence with Family (Box 62)
  - Correspondence with Carrie (Box 62 & 63)
  - Correspondence with Eustace (Box 64 & 65)
  - Correspondence with Frances (Box 65)
  - Correspondence with Mabel, 1905 (Box 66)
  - Correspondence with Mother, Mother Beer (Box 67)
  - Correspondence with Violet (Box 68 - 70)
  - Scrapbook (In Memoriam Alfred E. Seligman) (Box 70)
  - Portraits & medals, etc. (Box 71)
  - Higgs list--Seligman list (Box 72)
  - Mss. (Historical mss. collected by Seligman) (Box 73)
  - Bibliography, 1470-1929 (Box 74 & 75)
  - Financial histroy, notes (Box 76)
  - Financial histroy, manuscripts (Box 77 - 82)
  - Notes from lectures (Box 83)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 84 & 85)
  - Lecture notes taken while a student in Berlin, 1879-1981 (Box 86)
  - Berlin lecture notes and French lecture notes (Box 87)
  - Miscellaneous typescripts (not by Seligman) (Box 88)
  - N.Y.C. Taxation, 1911-1913; Maritime Union (Box 89)
  - N.Y.C. Taxation, 1914-1916 (one binder) (Box 90)
  - N.Y. State Commission on Revision of Tax Laws (Box 91)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials: Reports of Committees on which Seligman served (Box 92)
  - LeRoy-Beaulieu, Paul Clippings on finance written or collected by him, (6 scrapbooks) (Box 93 & 94)
  - Shirley, William Letters & documents (Box 95)
  - Flobart, Paul Recherches sur les billets de la banque de law (Box 96)
- Series III: Printed Material
  - Printed material re. Seligman (Box 98)
  - Printed material: Pamphlets and reprints inscribed to Seligman by authors, B-Z (Box 99 - 101)
  - Card catalog for Boxes 99 - 101 (Box 99)
  - Double Taxation unbound volumes, 1922 - 1923 (Box 115)
  - Double Taxation unbound volumes, 1923 - 1926 (Box 116)
- Series IV: Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1909 - 1910 (Box 102)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1910 - 1912 (Box 103)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1913 - 1914 (Box 104)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1915 - 1916 (Box 105)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1917 - 1918 (Box 106)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1918 - 1922 (Box 107)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1922 - 1925 (Box 108)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1925 - 1928 (Box 109)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1927 - 1929 (Box 110)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1929 - 1931 (Box 111)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1931 - 1932 (Box 112)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1932 - 1933 (Box 113)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Seligman, 1933 - 1938 (Box 114)
  - Bas-relief plaque (Box 638)
  - Memorabilia: Commemorative diploma celebrating the acquisition of the Louisiana territory (Box 14-16-04)
  - Photograph, signed, 59 x 22 cm. (Box 14-16-04)
- Series V: John Frances Bray Papers
  - Abstract of the Michigan Experience, 1842-1896 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - "Brief Sketch of the Life of John F. Bray - Social, Political and Religious Reformer", 1890, ( Photostat of original manuscript) (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Family records of births, marriage, death, ( Photostats) (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Family record; photostats of Bible entries (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - "God and Man A Unity", 1877, ( Original draft) (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - "God and Man A Unity", ( Manuscript) (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - "God and Man A Unity." The attempt is made to sell it and to pay for the printing (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - "God and Man A Unity." Bills for printing and 2 letters from Judson Grenell for selling the book (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - "God and Man A Unity" - Miscellaneous (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Log books, 1890-1894 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Reviews; Quotations, Advertisements from the Labor Review, Detroit, 1880-1882, ( photostats) (Box 97, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Ernest Charles Jones Papers, 1819-1969
  - Cataloged Materials
    - A (Box 1)
    - B-D (Box 2)
    - E-H (Box 3)
    - J-Jones, E.C. (Undated) (Box 4)
    - Jones, E.C. (Dated and MSS) (Box 5)
    - Jones, J.-Jones, W. (Box 6)
    - Ju-Q (Box 7)
    - R-Wy (end) (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, family and business papers: Two miscellaneous boxes (Box 9-10)